<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Announcement | SilverTiger Development]]></title>
  <link href="http://silvertiger.github.io/blog/categories/announcement/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://silvertiger.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-04T13:22:06+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://silvertiger.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Heiko Brumme]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LWJGL 3.0.0a Released!]]></title>
    <link href="http://silvertiger.github.io/blog/2015/04/28/lwjgl-3-0-0a-released/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-28T10:39:17+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://silvertiger.github.io/blog/2015/04/28/lwjgl-3-0-0a-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally the first official release of the Lightweight Java Game Library is done, with Version 3.0.0a there where a few changes.</p>

<p>One of the important changes are the type postfixes of some functions, it will break some older code, but it can be easily fixed.</p>

<p>So what comes next? It seems like LWJGL3 is going to get support for Gradle and a binding to AMD&rsquo;s Mantle, so that you can practice for the upcoming Vulkan API of Khronos because it is based on Mantle.</p>

<p>For more information on this release have a look at the <a href="http://blog.lwjgl.org/lwjgl-3-0a-released/">official blog post</a>.<br/>
You can get the release version in the <a href="http://www.lwjgl.org/download">download section of lwjgl.org</a> or <a href="http://build.lwjgl.org/release/3.0.0a/lwjgl-3.0.0a.zip">directly by clicking here</a>.</p>

<p>In the next few days I will update the tutorial for LWJGL3 and will upload the last part of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to My Blog!]]></title>
    <link href="http://silvertiger.github.io/blog/2014/11/29/welcome-to-my-blog/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-29T03:47:35+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://silvertiger.github.io/blog/2014/11/29/welcome-to-my-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First I have to thank <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> for a great blogging framework and <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub</a> for providing this page!</p>

<p>&lsquo;So what is this blog about?&rsquo; you may ask. I will use this blog to show you game development with Java and OpenGL.<br/>
When you hear OpenGL and Java you will probably also hear about these two libraries:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://jogamp.org/jogl/www/">JOGL</a> is a part of JogAmp, which provides you with bindings to OpenGL, OpenCL, OpenAL and OpenMAX.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.lwjgl.org/">LWJGL</a> stands for Lightweight Java Game Library and provides you also with bindings to OpenGL, OpenCL and OpenAL.</li>
</ul>


<p>So it is up to you which to use, they are both great libraries for high-performant computer graphics programming with Java. Personally I use the LWJGL for graphics programming.</p>

<h2>About me</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m a computer science student from Germany and in a few weeks I will start my bachelor&rsquo;s thesis about computer graphics.<br/>
During my course of studies I learned programming with Scheme, Java, C# and C++. Well I also learned PHP and JavaScript but that were merely the basics in my opinion.</p>

<p>In my free time I am a gamer and a programmer, or just lurking around in the Internet, for example you could find me on <a href="http://www.java-gaming.org/">JGO</a> which is a small community of Java game programmers, so if you like Java game development you should check it out!</p>

<h2>Next Steps</h2>

<p>Soon I will start a tutorial for the new LWJGL3 in which I will show you how to use the that library to create a simple game! I&rsquo;m looking forward for it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
